And welcome back to our challenge again.
そして､ また我々の挑戦に戻ってきてくれたことを歓迎する｡
And this time we are working with our beautiful prototype.
そして今回は､ 私たちの美しいプロトタイプを使っている｡
Uh, with this time the default set to the Python Hard challenge rather than the simple pi code.
ええと､ 今回のデフォルトは､ 単純なπコードではなく､ Python Hardチャレンジに設定されています｡
We bring this up.
私たちはこれを持ち出した｡
Here it is.
これだ｡
We're going to kick off the Python run, which you may remember takes about 2720 eight seconds.
Pythonの実行を開始し､ 約2720 8秒かかることを覚えているかもしれない｡
So we'll be sitting here for a little while.
だから､ しばらくここに座っていることになる｡
While that runs, I am then going to do use GPT to convert the code to C plus plus and run that.
その間に､ GPTを使ってコードをCプラスプラスに変換し､ それを実行するつもりだ｡
And then we'll do the same with Claude and see how Claude fares and see if there are any differences
そして､ クロードにも同じことをやって､ クロードがどう出るか､ 前回との違いがあるかどうかを見る｡
Uh, almost there.
もう少しだ｡
You can watch Gradio gives us a little timer, which is very handy in these situations.
Gradioが小さなタイマーを提供してくれるのを見ることができる｡
So we'll know that there we go.
だから､ 私たちはそのことを知ることになる｡
We get the answer that is the right answer.
私たちは正しい答えを得る｡
And it took about 28 seconds.
そして約28秒かかった｡
All right.
分かった｡
We asked GPT to convert this into C plus plus code.
私たちはGPTにこれをC＋＋のコードに変換するよう依頼した｡
Here is the C plus plus code.
これがCプラスプラスのコードだ｡
There is the result.
これが結果だ｡
And we will then run that C plus plus code.
そして､ そのCプラスプラスのコードを実行する｡
And it has the same problem as before.
そして､ 以前と同じ問題を抱えている｡
There's I believe it's a number overflow that's resulting in the answer being zero and not even that
数字がオーバーフローして､ 答えがゼロになっているのだと思う｡
quick.
というのも､ その答えにゼロを与える際に､ いくつかの入れ子ループも起こっていたからだ｡
Let's see how Claude fares.
クロードがどう出るか見てみよう｡
We switch to Claude, we convert the code.
クロードに切り替え､ コードを変換する｡
Here we go.
さあ､ 始めよう｡
Let's see what Claude has done.
クロードが何をしたか見てみよう｡
Aha!
嗚呼！
Interestingly, this time Claude has not seen that it can do the single loop.
興味深いことに､ 今回のクロードはシングルループができることを確認していない｡
So we've got a different answer from Claude this time.
そこで､ 今回はクロードから別の答えをもらった｡
There we go.
これでよし｡
We'll see how Claude does if its code runs.
クロードのコードが実行されれば､ どうなるか見てみよう｡
At least let's run that C plus.
せめてCプラスを走らせよう｡
Plus it got the right answer and it took 0.6 seconds.
それに､ 正しい答えを導き出したし､ 時間も0だった｡  6秒｡
So Claude at least gets the right answer.
だからクロードは少なくとも正しい答えを得た｡
But it is not this time.
だが､ 今回は違う｡
This time that we ran with Claude.
今回はクロードと一緒に走った｡
It didn't crush it like last time, because it didn't actually spot that opportunity to to to collapse
前回のように潰せなかったのは､ キヤノンのアルゴリズムでループを崩すチャンスを見つけられなかったからだ｡
And now remember it's called.
そして今､ それがこう呼ばれていることを思い出してほしい｡
So I guess we can try one more time converting the code and see if it if it gets it on a second attempt.
だから､ もう1回コードを変換してみて､ 2回目にうまくいくかどうか試してみよう｡
Let's see.
見てみよう｡
Let's see, let's see.
見てみよう､ 見てみよう｡
That does look like it's one loop doesn't it.
1つのループのように見えるね｡
All right.
分かった｡
Let's let's see if it's, uh, that's going to work for us.
それがうまくいくかどうか､ 確かめよう｡
It did work.
うまくいったよ｡
Second time lucky.
2度目の幸運だ｡
We get the right answer.
私たちは正しい答えを得る｡
And again we have that breathtaking.
またしても息をのむような展開になった｡
Oh my goodness.
なんてことだ｡
It's a whole lot better than last time as well.
前回よりも全然いい｡
Obviously there's some, uh, dependency on what else is running on on my processor.
明らかに､ 僕のプロセッサーで他に何が動いているかに依存している｡
We're probably down to the sort of the noise levels, but that is 0.4 of a, uh, of a millisecond,
おそらく騒音レベルまで下がっているだろうが､ それは0だ｡  4ミリ秒の､ ああ､ ミリ秒の､ ああ､
uh, compared to, uh, let's do the maths one more time.
もう一回計算してみよう｡
It's embarrassing that I can't do these sort of orders of magnitude in my head, but I'm too afraid
こういう桁違いのことが頭の中でできないのは恥ずかしいことだが､ あまりに大きくずれてしまうのが怖くてできない｡
28.3 divided by 0.000446.
28. 3÷0. 000446.
Uh, it's more than 60,000 times faster.
ええと､ 60,000倍以上速いんだ｡
Uh, which, of course, is not that surprising given that it's found an algorithm that involves a single
もちろん､ ネストされたループではなく､ 単一のループを含むアルゴリズムを発見したことを考えれば､
loop rather than a nested loop, but it is great to see that.
それほど驚くべきことではないが､ それを見るのは素晴らしいことだ｡
So in summary, Claude managed to to to work where GPT four failed.
まとめると､ クロードはGPT4が失敗したところをなんとか成功させたということだ｡
And Claude sometimes not always, is breathtakingly faster.
そして､ クロードは常にではないが､ 息をのむほど速い｡
Breathtaking, I will say, from doing my experiments that there were a couple of occasions when Claude
息を呑むようなことだが､ クロードも四捨五入を間違えて､
also made a mistake with the number rounding and and both Claude and GPT four zero got zero.
クロードとGPTの4人がゼロになったことが何度かあった｡
But GPT four zero seems to consistently make that mistake.
しかし､ GPTフォーゼロは一貫してその間違いを犯しているようだ｡
And more often than not, Claude not only gets it right, but also spots this opportunity to rewrite
そして多くの場合､ クロードはそれを正しく理解するだけでなく､ アルゴリズムを書き換えて驚異的に速くなるチャンスを見つける｡
So I think, again, I double down and say, this is a victory for Claude.
だから､ もう一度言うが､ これはクロードの勝利だ｡
Um, and then next week we are going to switch to open source.
それから来週はオープンソースに切り替える予定だ｡
We're going to assess open source models.
オープンソースのモデルを評価するつもりだ｡
We're going to see how open source models generate code and use a solution with open source Llms.
オープンソースのモデルがどのようにコードを生成し､ オープンソースのLlmsを使ったソリューションを使うかを見ていく｡
The question will be can open source compete with Claude?
問題は､ オープンソースがクロードに対抗できるかどうかだ｡
3.5 sonnet.
3. 5ソネット
Uh, with this astoundingly fast, uh, result.
ええと､ この驚くべき速さで､ ええと､ 結果が出た｡
See you then.
ではまた